Burd-Shippen Papers 1708-1792 Mss.B.B892
American Philosophical Society
- Receipts, 1746-1792; Series V; .75 lin. feet
  - Receipts to Dennis McCormick, 1764 August 4; 2 pp.; Wallace, William (Box 10)
    For driving sheep to Fort Augusta, and for the sheep.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1764 October 6; 1p.; Stoner, John (Box 10)
    For flour and buckwheat.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1764 October 26; 1p.; Young, Henry (Box 10)
    For coffin.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1764 October 29; 1p.; Brewbaker, John (Box 10)
    For wood.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1764 October 30; 1p.; Brewbaker, David (Box 10)
    For smelts.
  - Receipt to Dennis McCormick, 1764 November 3; 1p.; Forester, James (Box 10)
    For steer.
  - Receipt to Dennis McCormick, 1764 November 22; 1p.; Stephens, Alexander (Box 10)
    For carriage of 1 barrel of salt.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1764 December 12; 1p.; Keelan, James (Box 10)
    For painting a "New Floor Cloath."
  - Receipt, 1764; 1p.; Cameron, John (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 January 8; 1p.; Stonner, John (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 January 10; 1p.; Mayer, George (Box 10)
    For a "Wigg."
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 March 6; 1p.; Willing & Morris (Box 10)
    For wine, Old Tayall, brandy, rum, sugar, coffee.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 March 6; 1p.; David Shaffer & Co. (Box 10)
    For sugar, etc..
  - Receipt to Col. Burd ", 1765 March 8; 1p.; Gallagher, Andrew (Box 10)
    For "dressing #x0026; shaving.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 March 8; 1p.; Hiltzheimer, Jacob (Box 10)
    For keeping his horse.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 March 19; 1p.; Shade, George (Box 10)
    For cartage from Philadelphia to Lancaster.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 April 15; 1p.; Diefendörfer, Michel (Box 10)
    For carrying 2 pipes of wine to Lancaster.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 April 22; 1p.; Miller, John and Jacob Dicker (Box 10)
    For making shingles.
  - Receipt to Dennis McCormick, 1765 May 10; 1p.; Montgomery, Hugh (Box 10)
    For cartage of salt.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 May 13; 1p.; Hoofnagle, John and William (Box 10)
    For digging the cellar.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 May 14; 1p.; Campbell, James (Box 10)
    For carriage of wine.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 May 17; 1p.; Burckhart, George (Box 10)
    For "Poppler Boards."
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 June 3; 1p.; Marshall, William (Box 10)
    For cartage of "limmons."
  - Receipt to Joseph Shippen, 1765 June 23; 1p.; Allen, George (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 June 24; 1p.; Reach, Joseph (Box 10)
    For rum, brandy, and lemmons.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 August 20; 1p.; Simon & Henry (Box 10)
    For nails, etc.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 August 20; 1p.; Smith, Ephram (Box 10)
    For sugar.
  - Receipt, 1765 September 6; 1p.; Willing & Morris (Box 10)
    For £11.2.21.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 November 15; 1p.; Taylor, John (Box 10)
    For "Lemmons."
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 December 12; 1p.; McCord, Robert (Box 10)
    For payment for hogs.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 December 16; 1p.; Hoffnagle, William and Abraham Stycherwell (Box 10)
    For making a fence.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 December 17; 1p.; Glasford, Hugh (Box 10)
    For "linnen."
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1765 December 18; 1p.; Davidson, James (Box 10)
    For barrels, and sundrys.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1766 January 8; 1p.; Doen, Phillip (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1766 January 28; 1p.; Hambright & Musier (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1766 March 6; 1p.; Spoor, John (Box 10)
    For stone.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1766 March 27; 1p.; Fulton, Robert and Mary (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1766 July 3; 1p.; McCormick, Dennis (Box 10)
    For nails, flour, etc.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1766 August 8; 1p.; Wirtz, Christian (Box 10)
    For "Linnen", silk handkerchief, and glover seed.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1766 September 8; 1p. (Box 10)
    For planks.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1766 September 19; 1p.; McWhorter, William (Box 10)
    For grubbing up ground.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1766 October 24; 1p.; Hetherinton, John (Box 10)
    For rails, stakes, and two days work.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1766 November 10; 1p.; Wyrick, Anthony (Box 10)
    For shingles, clap boards, and work time.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1767 July 18; 1p.; Wooley, Peter (Box 10)
    For £1 on the account of John Penn for vermillion for the use of the Six Nations.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1767 August 14; 1p.; Kenadey, James (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1767 September 18; 1p.; Enrich, Anthony (Box 10)
    For wind mill.
  - Receipt to the Committee of the Pennsylvania Regiment, 1767; 1p.; Slough, Mathias (Box 10)
    For their expenses at his house.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1768 January 5; 1p.; Amos, Ann (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1768 April 29; 1p.; Berreyhill, Andrew (Box 10)
    For £1.19.7.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1768 April 28; 1p.; Brand, Jacob (Box 10)
    For rye.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1768 September 22, 23; 1p.; Coope, Caleb and John Seely (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1768 October 21; 1p.; Field, John (Box 10)
    For work.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1768 October 22; 1p.; Everhard, Frederick (Box 10)
    For £0.12.6.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1768 November 15; 1p.; Wilson, James (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1768 November 21; 1p.; Kenedy, James (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1769 February 14; 1p.; Berryhill, Andrew (Box 10)
    For debt.
  - Receipt to James Burd., 1769 March 16; 1p.; Poultney, Thomas (Box 10)
    For purchase of nails, axes, etc.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1769 November 2; 1p.; Spade, Christian and George Sowman (Box 10)
    For painting house and building chimney, etc.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 176- January 5; 1p.; McKees, Daniel (Box 10)
    For pay and subsistance money as a soldier.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1770 January 15; 1p.; Leadie, Sampson (Box 10)
    For clapboard, etc.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1770 March 23; 1p.; Robinson, Samuel (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1770 June 20; 1p.; Postlethwait, John (Box 10)
    For hogs.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1770 July 4; 1p.; Gaskins, Thomas (Box 10)
    For £3.7.6.
  - Receipt to Revd. Richard Peters, 1770 August 24; 1p.; Elder, Josuah (Box 10)
    For surveying two tracts.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1770 September 6; 1p.; McMullen, Daniel (Box 10)
    For threshing.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1770 October 8; 1p.; Craig, John (Box 10)
    For weaving cloth.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1770 November 10; 1p.; Poultney, Thomas (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1770; 1p.; Brauch (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1771 April 10; 1p.; Rutherford, Thomas (Box 10)
    For butter.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1771 May 18; 1p.; Willis, Abner (Box 10)
    For axes and "steeling three old axes."
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1771 November 2; 1p.; Hutchinson, Joseph (Box 10)
    For debts.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1772 January 3; 1p. [split into two]; McWharters, William (Box 10)
    For clearing 5 acres, splitting rails, etc.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1772 March 7; 1p.; Wickersham, E. (Box 10)
    For paper, rum, etc.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1772 June 25; 1p.; Haldeman, Christy (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1772 August 8; 1p.; Herbert, Stewart, Jr. (Box 10)
    For printing summons.
  - Receipt, 1772 December 3; 1p.; Frey, George (Box 10)
    For salt, indigo, etc.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1773 June 29; 1p.; Wickersham, E. (Box 10)
    For meat, needles, etc.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1773 September 15; 1p.; Elisha & A. Wickersham (Box 10)
    For rum, sugar, mace, clover, and a stone jug.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1774 January 18; 1p.; Crouch, James (Box 10)
    For apple trees.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1774 March 3; 1p.; Frey, George (Box 10)
    For ribbon, etc.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1774 April 22; 1p.; Woolfly, Conrad (Box 10)
    For beef.
  - Receipt to Mrs. Halm, 1774 April; 2pp.; Wickersham, Elijah and Abner (Box 10)
    For butter, silk, etc.
  - Receipt, 1774 June 11; 1p.; Frey, George (Box 10)
    For rum, molasses, brown sugar, white gaze, and tin cups..
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1774 June 22; 2pp.; Boyd, Joseph (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1774 August 12; 1p.; Graff, Sebastian (Box 10)
    On account.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1774 August 27; 1p.; Bowl, Henry (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1774 December 3; 1p.; Williams, george (Box 10)
    For oats, etc.
  - Receipt to William Cork, 1775 March 6; 1p.; Hines, John (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1775 May 24; 1p.; Forbes & Patton (Box 10)
    For sugar and rum.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1775 May 25; 1p.; Blyth, William (Box 10)
    For £0.10.6.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1775 November 28; 1p.; Barnett, William (Box 10)
    For salt, etc.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1776 December 18; 1p.; Oberlander, C. Frederick (Box 10)
    For sugar, coffee, etc.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1776 December 19; 1p.; Oberlander, C. Frederick (Box 10)
    For buckles, thread, etc.
  - Receipt to Albright Shear, 1778 February 20; 1p.; Creamer, Jacob (Box 10)
    For taxes.
  - Receipt to George Williams, 1778 August 12; 1p.; Harris, John, 1726-1791 (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1780 October 11; 1p.; Craft, Philip (Box 10)
    For two men.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1781 May 23; 1p.; McClure, William (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1783 May 5; 1p.; Allen, Joseph (Box 10)
    For teaching his son, Joseph.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1789 May 4; 1p.; Shurter, Peter (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1790 July 3; 1p.; Robert, Thomas (Box 10)
    For newspaper.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1790 July 8; 1p.; Riddles, George (Box 10)
    For brown sugar.
  - Receipt to James Burd, 1792 June 16; 1p.; Cowgill, Jonah for George Riddles (Box 10)
    For purchase of brown sugar, needles, and thread.
  - Receipt to Michael Edinborough, 1792 August 10; 1p.; Duncan, James (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, January 20; 1p.; Phillips, John, Jr. (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, February 6; 1p.; Gibson, George, 1747-1791 (Box 10)
    For hay, oats.
  - Receipt to James Burd, June 5; 1p.; Cooper, William (Box 10)
    For £4.12.0.
  - Bill to Robert Fulton, n.d.; 1p.; Adams, John (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, n.d.; 1p.; Barrant, James (Box 10)
    For all tools.
  - Receipt to James Burd, n.d.; 1p.; Forbes & Patton (Box 10)
  - Receipt to James Burd, n.d.; 1p.; Luckens, John (Box 10)
  - Receipt, n.d.; 1p.; Shippen, Joseph (Box 10)
- Bound Volumes, 1747-1787; Series IV; 12 volumes
  Account books and ledgers for James Burd's businesses; orderly books, receipt books and account books for Burd's company and Fort Augusta; and one volume of printed forms. Of note are the diaries relating events at Fort Augusta, and a journal of the seige of Fort William Henry.
  - Day Ledger, 1747-1749; 657 B892.1; 1 vol.
    Philadelphia, PA. Record of purchases; customers include: William Biddle, Mrs. Breintnall, Edward Shippen, Joseph Shippen, Dr. William Shippen, and Charles Stedman.
    Bound in parchment,containing 171 leaves, of which 13 are without writing.
  - Account Books, 1747-1748; 657 B892.3; 1 vol.
    Philadelphia, PA. Notes of materials in stock (tammys, prunellos, florettas, serpentines, inkpots, knives, rugs, razors, etc.); records of sales. At the end a member of the Burd family at Shippensburg, Pa., has copied legal forms, "Rules for Health," recipes and prescriptions, etc., ca. 1811-1816.
  - Account book, 1749-1751; 657 B89a; 1 vol.
    Philadelphia, PA. Accounts, profit and loss statements, records of shipments.
  - Muster Roll for Major Burd's Company, 1757 May - October; 973.2 B89m; 1vol.
    Lists officers and men's names, date of enlistment or commission, term of enlistment, age, and trade (not all information given). In addition, lists payments, and notes of encampments.
  - Major Burd's Account Book, 1753-1763; 973.2 B89a; 1 vol.
    List of accounts with soldiers under his command.
  - Orderly Book, Fort Augusta, 1757; 973.2 B89o; 1 vol.
    List of orders given, officer of the guard, along with parole and countersign. Top right corner of book is missing throughout.
  - Major Burd's Receipt Book, 1757; 973.2 B89r; 1 vol.
    Receipts for payment to soldiers in Major Burd's company. Mentions sale of flour to Indians; sale of flour to Carolina Indians; Teedyuskung mentioned. Record of Major Hunter's mess and Major Graydon's mess.
  - Major Burd's Receipt and account book, 1756; 973.2 B89rs; 1 vol.
    Fort Granville. Lists payments to soldiers, and items purchased.
  - Diaries, 1760 June-November, 1763 June-December; 973.2 D54; 2 vols.
    Dated account of events at Fort Augusta, detailing troop movements, soldiers present, and encounters with Indians. Kept by James Burd, Samuel Hunter, and others. Various officers record Indian trouble, treaty session (1760), role of John Shickellamy as informant, scalpings, skirmishes, contacts.
  - Journal of Seige of Fort William Henry, 2-10 August 1757; 973.2 F77; 1.0 Item(s) 1 volume, 6 leaves.
    Account of events during the seige of Fort William Henry. Regarding the participation of Indians in the siege; atrocities committed by the Indians; failure of the French to attempt any control; receipt of plunder by the French from the Indians.
  - Sale book, Book C, 1747-1748; 657 B892; 1 vol.
    Philadelphia, PA. Record of sales. Orgainzed by items -- listing who the items were purchased from and to whom sold. The volume also includes the ledger of Joseph Burd of Tinian, Dauphin County, Pa., 1810, with notes, receipts, memoranda, recipes, and cures for certain ailments.
  - Account book, 1750-1756, 1752-1753; 657 B892.2; 1 vol.
    Philadelphia, PA and Shippensburg, PA. Sales of beer, malt, hops, wood, barrels; also of rugs, blankets, gunpowder, cambric, etc. Customers include: William Allen, James Benezet, Alexander Graydon, Edward Shippen, Joseph Shippen, Robert Smith.
  - Account book and index, 1765-1768; 657 B89b; 2 vols.
    Lancaster, PA. Among the customers are the suppliers of Fot Augusta. Note in volume from L. L. Nixon indicates that this is account of Burd's wine shop in Lancaster after leaving the army in 1675, and before buying his Tinian plantation.
  - Printed forms, 1747-1787; B B892p; 1 vol.
    Contains forms for enlistments in the Province of Pennsylvania, military passes, report of chimneys, receipts for victuals at Fort Augusta, blank bond for the loan of books by the Lancaster Library Company, indenture of servants, writs of capias, King's warrants signed by James Burd, Summons, bills of exchange with Virginia and Maryland, and bills of lading. With the exception of a few blanks, the forms have been filled in. A list is included on the first page.